Hansraj Das, Senior Software Engineer at Globallogic

rajdas223@gmail.com | 09971811734 | New Delhi, Delhi, India https://github.com/hansrajdas

SUMMARY

Seasoned software engineer with extensive experience in software/web development, testing and maintenance of complex products. Most of the work experience revolve around Python, C/C++ and Golang. Good understanding of databases - MySQL, SQLite and LDAP. In depth understanding of algorithms, data structures, time/space complexity and OOPs concepts. Posses good knowledge of designing/architecting, testing and deployment of softwares on various platforms. Also have hands on experience in front end frameworks/libraries - AngularJS, jQuery and python modules like numpy and pandas. Currently working as a developer for Google as TVC @Google Gurgaon, India.

SKILLS Languages (Master): Python, C/C++, Shell Scripting

Languages (Intermediate): Golang, Javascript, CSS, HTML

Framework (Intermediate): AngularJS, jQuery, Numpy, Pandas, SQLAlchemy, Webapp2

Databases (Master): MySQL, LDAP

Software Tools (Master): Vim, Wireshark, Gdb, Valgrind, Callgrind, Purify, Bullseye, Jenkins

Server (*Master*): Apache, Socket programming **Version Control** (*Master*): GIT, CVS, SVN

Operating System (Master): Ubuntu, Unix, Linux, Windows

Cloud Platform Tools (Intermediate): Google Appengine(GAE), Google Cloud SQL, Borg/Kubernetes

EXPERIENCE

GlobalLogic

Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2017 — Present

https://globallogic.com

- Working on 2 google internal tools
- Improved tools performance, latency from 20 secs to 5 secs
- Implemented bulk edit functionality to update agent profiles in batches Based in Golang, Jquery, and CloudSQL
- Developed python and agularJS based tool to manage agent assignments
- Also working on various pipelines, dashboards, deployment platforms like google app engine, borg/kubernetes

Aricent, Gurgaon

Technical Leader

Oct 2011 — Mar 2017

https://www.aricent.com/

- Majorly involved in development of HSS REST interface and LTE EPC
- Developed XML based REST interface to configure LTE HSS using python, C/C++, gSoap and apache web server
- Developed support for distributed HSS in EMS, EMS is a web based tool to configure LTE EPC nodes.
 Technologies used is python, C/C++, javascript and HTML
- Developed a python based tool to migrate routing configurations stored at ldap server (in ldif files) on new hardware platform
- Developed S6a and STa interface in HSS, in depth knowledge of diameter protocol
- Integrated all LTE EPC core network nodes (MME, SGW, PGW, HSS and PCRF)

AWARDS

Individual Excellence Award, Globallogic

o Got individual excellence award for quarter Jan-Mar 2018

Aricent Training Project, Aricent

• Won second prize for training project (network firewall) at aricent, Jan 2012

EDUCATION

Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering

Aug 2007 — Jun 2011

B.Tech - Electronics and Communication, GPA: 73.4%

Kendriya Vidyalaya, Rohini, Delhi

XII - Science, GPA: 86.4%

Apr 2006 — Jun 2007

LANGUAGES

Hindi (Native speaker (mother tongue)), English (Native speaker)